Bennet, William Stiles; Papers apap226
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
William Stiles Bennet Papers
1884-1959
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap226
12.42 cubic ft.
The William Stiles Bennet Papers document some of his public service and political campaigns as well as his time as a lobbyist and advocate for the lumber industry.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
The W. S. Bennet Estate initially donated Bennet's papers to Syracuse University in 1965. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Organizational Sketch
William Stiles Bennet was a U.S. Representative from New York. He was the father of Augustus Witschief Bennet, who also served as a U.S. Representative.
Bennet was born in Port Jervis, NY on November 9, 1870. He attended the common schools, graduated from Port Jervis Academy in 1889, and received his law degree from Albany Law School in 1892.
Bennet was a lawyer in private practice, an official reporter of the Orange County Board of Supervisors (1892-1893), a member of the New York State Assembly (1901-1902), a Justice of the Municipal Court of New York City (1903), a member of the United States Immigration Commission (1907-1910), and a delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1908 and 1916. He served as a Republican in the 59th through 61st Congresses (March 4, 1905-March 3, 1911) and was an unsuccessful candidate for reelection in 1910. He was elected to the 64th Congress to fill the vacancy caused by the death of U.S. Representative Joseph A. Goulden (November 2, 1915-March 3, 1917), but was an unsuccessful candidate for reelection to the 65th Congress in 1916. Bennet served as the official parliamentarian of the Republican National Convention at Chicago in 1916 and was a United States delegate to the Seventeenth International Congress Against Alcoholism held in Copenhagen in 1923.
From 1920 to 1933 Bennet served as General Counsel to the Edward Hines Lumber Company. During the later 1930s and 1940s he served as a lobbyist and advocate for the lumber industry. He was an unsuccessful candidate for election to the 75th Congress in 1936. That same year Bennet also unsuccessfully sought the Republican nomination for Vice President. He received the nomination in the Oregon primary due to his connection with the lumber industry in that state, but by the time of the national Republican Convention he was no longer considered a viable candidate and lost the nomination to Frank Knox of Illinois. He served as a delegate to the New York State Constitutional Convention in 1938. He ran unsuccessfully in a special election in 1944 to fill a vacancy in the 78th Congress.
Bennet died on December 1, 1962, in Central Valley, NY. His ashes are interred in Laurel Grove Cemetery in Port Jervis, NY.
Scope and Contents
The William Stiles Bennet Papers document the personal and professional activities of William Stiles Bennet. They date primarily from the years 1930-1960.
Series 1, Subject File, is organized alphabetically by subject. It contains Bennet's extensive files on various personal and professional subjects and dates primarily from the 1930s through the 1950s. This series include extensive files on the Forest-Algoma and Weyerhaeuser lumber companies, files on numerous individuals whom Bennet represented as an immigration lawyer, and material on the 1938 New York State Constitutional Convention. It also includes material related to philanthropic organizations such as the National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor and the National Bible Society.
Series 2, Incoming Correspondence, contains correspondence received by William Stiles Bennet. Outside of a few brief items from the 1890s, material in this series dates from the years 1930 through 1959. These items are arranged chronologically.
Series 3, Outgoing Correspondence, contains outgoing correspondence sent by William Stiles Bennet. These materials date from the 1930s through the 1950s and are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
Series 4, Political Materials and Oversized Items, contains materials related to Bennet's various political campaigns as well as several oversized and fragile items. It includes a folder of speeches delivered by Bennet to the New York State Assembly in 1901-1902, several folders of material on Bennet's unsuccessful 1936 campaign for the Republican Vice Presidential nomination, and collections of political memorabilia from various campaigns. In addition, it includes several large scrapbooks, the transcription of an oral history interview with Bennet, tax reports from the town of Newburgh, a ledger dating from the late nineteenth century, and a collection of certificates documenting Bennet's election to various offices.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Subject File, 1922-1959, Undated
Series 2 - Incoming Correspondence, 1884-1959, Undated
Series 3 - Outgoing Correspondence, 1932-1959, Undated
Series 4 - Political Materials and Oversized Items, 1888-1951, Undated
Series 1 and 3 are arranged alphabetically while Series 2 and 4 are arranged chronologically.
Politics and Politicians; Scrapbooks; Correspondence; Immigration Records; Legal Files; Speeches (documents); Campaigns; Bennet, William S. (William Stiles), 1870-1962; New York (State). Constitutional Convention (1938); National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor (U.S.); Edward Hines Lumber Co.; Forest-Algoma Lumber Company; Weyerhaeuser Company; Weyerhaeuser Timber Company; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly
- Subject File, 1922-1959; Undated; 1; 7.5 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series is organized alphabetically by subject. It contains Bennet's extensive files on various personal and professional subjects and dates primarily from the 1930s through the 1950s. This series include extensive files on the Forest-Algoma and Weyerhaeuser lumber companies, files on numerous individuals whom Bennet represented as an immigration lawyer, and material on the 1938 New York State Constitutional Convention. It also includes material related to philanthropic organizations such as the National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor and the National Bible Society.
  - Albrecht, Carl Heinrich, Immigration Records, 1951-1955 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 1)
  - Algoma Lumbar Company Correspondence, 1951-1955; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 2-4)
  - Algoma Lumbar Company, Legal File #1, 1936-1938; 1943-1950; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 5-7)
  - Algoma Lumbar Company, Legal File #2, 1934-1940; 1951-1954; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 8)
  - Algoma Lumbar Company, Lobbying Forms, 1947-1948; 1950; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 9)
  - American League for a Free Palestine, 1946-1949 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 10-11)
  - Anderson, Carl J., Correspondence, 1946-1951 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 12)
  - Anderson, Carl J., Naturalization and Miscellaneous Memos, 1947-1949 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 13)
  - Anti-Lynching Bill, 1936-1951 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 14)
  - Barker, Mrs. Percival H, 1937 November; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 15)
  - Bennet, Howell S, 1938-1951 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 16)
  - Bennet, James E, 1938-1947 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 17-18)
  - Bennet, James E, 1948-1952 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 19)
  - Boxill, Mrs. Vera, 1922-1952 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 20)
  - Boxill, Mrs. Vera, Miscellaneous, 1938-1954 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 21)
  - Chariton, Mrs. Bessie, 1951-1953 (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 22)
  - Ching, Peter Pan-Shih (Immigration) (Folders 1-3 of 4), 1950-1959; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject File), Folder 23-25)
  - Ching, Peter Pan-Shih (Immigration) (Folder 4 of 4), 1950-1959; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject File), Folder 1)
  - Citroen, Mariane, 1951-1959; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject File), Folder 2-9)
  - Edward Hines Lumber Co. Correspondence, 1932; 1943-1949; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject File), Folder 10-12)
  - Forest Lumber Company, 1938-1940; 1951-1957; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject File), Folder 13-15)
  - Forest Lumber Company and Algoma Lumbar Company Court Cases (Folders 1-2 of 3), 1934; 1938-1954; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject File), Folder 16-17)
  - Forest Lumber Company and Algoma Lumbar Company Court Cases (Folder 3 of 3), 1934; 1938-1954; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 1)
  - Forest Lumber Company and Algoma Lumbar Company Court Case Correspondence, 1939; 1951-1952 (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 2-3)
  - Forest Lumber Company and Algoma Lumbar Company Miscellaneous, 1939-1942; 1946; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 4-6)
  - Forest Lumber Company and Algoma Lumbar Company vs. US, Current, 1951-1958; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 7-10)
  - Gates, Charles W Jr. (Immigration), 1949 (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 11)
  - Gee, Mee Haw (Immigration), 1953-1954; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 12)
  - Gill, James W. (Immigration), 1950-1959; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 13-17)
  - Haac, Ernest Ottomar, 1949; 1954; 1958-1959 (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 18)
  - Immigration Correspondence and Applications, 1947-1950; 1954; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 19)
  - In Convention Records, 1938 (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 20-21)
  - Kafiluddin, L.S. (Immigration), 1952-1953 (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 22)
  - Legal Opinion on Immunity of Port Authority Bonds and Revenues from Federal Income Taxation, 1938 (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 23)
  - Letters to Newspapers, 1938-1945 (Box 3 (1-Subject File), Folder 24)
  - Letters to Newspapers, 1974-1953 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 1)
  - Lukac, Peter, 1953-1955; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 2)
  - Lukac, Peter and Suzanne, Legislative Bills, Drafts, Notes, Working Papers, 1948-1954; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 3)
  - Lukac, Peter and Suzanne Official Papers, 1947-1955; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 4)
  - Lukac, Suzanne, Legal File, 1947-1958 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 4-6)
  - Mount Vernon Republican Club, 1943-1944; 1949-1951 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 7)
  - National Committees on Prisons and Prison Labor, 1942-1947 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 8-9)
  - National Committees on Prisons and Prison Labor, 1947-1948; 1957 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 10)
  - National Committees on Prisons and Prison Labor Agendas, Booklets, Correspondence, and Meeting Minutes, 1917; 1927-1953; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 11-15)
  - National Committees on Prisons and Prison Labor Correspondence and Expenses, 1952-1955 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 16)
  - National Committees on Prisons and Prison Labor, Kendall Estate, 1948-1954 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 17)
  - National Republican Club, Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 18-19)
  - New York Bible Society Agendas, Correspondence, Meeting Minutes, Reports and Pamphlets, 1950-1958 (Box 4 (1-Subject File), Folder 20-23)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention, 1928 April-1941 June (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 1-4)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention Booklets, 1937-1938; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 5)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention Correspondence, Statements and Pamphlets, 1894; 1937-1938; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 6-8)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention, Proposed Amendments, 1938 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 9-10)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention Record and Index, 1938 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 11)
  - The New York Young Republican Club, 1938 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 12)
  - Nuveen Family, Correspondence, 1954-1959 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 13)
  - Opinion of Immunity from Federal Income Taxes, 1938 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 14)
  - Papaconstantinou, Constantinos, Immigration, 1956-1957; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 15)
  - Paraulos, Spiros (Immigration), 1952; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 16)
  - Parmentier's Roses, Legal File, 1954 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 17)
  - Pedersen, John D., Correspondence, 1940 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 18-19)
  - Pedersen, John D., Drafts and Memos, 1939-1940; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 20-21)
  - Pierce, Florence, 1939-1959 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 22)
  - Pisani, Simone (Immigration), 1951-1955; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 23)
  - Post-War Plans, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 24)
  - Quoch, Lunge (Immigration), 1953-1959; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 25-26)
  - Reed, Lily W., Legal File, 1949; 1954-1958; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 27-28)
  - Religion Notes, 1953-1955; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 29)
  - Republican National Committee, 1932-1936; 1944-1950; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject File), Folder 30)
  - Request for Copies of 1910 Peace Resolution, 1949 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 11)
  - Request for Copy of 1910 Peace Resolution and Nicholas Murray Butler Speeches, 1938-1942 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 2)
  - Reynolds, Mark and Ann, 1955-1956; 1958 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 3)
  - Santiago, Carol Immigration, 1952-1958; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 4)
  - Schweitzer, Theodore, 1955; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 5)
  - Serigos, Emanuel, 1952 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 6)
  - Slavata, George (Immigration), 1950-1954; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 7)
  - Society of the Massing of the Colors, 1945; 1949 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 8)
  - Special Assistant Attorney's General Reports Re: Election, 1935; 1938 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 9)
  - Speeches, 1941 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 10)
  - Speeches, 1944 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 11)
  - Speeches, Correspondence and Drafts, 1923-1946; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 12-16)
  - Speeches, Drafts, 1934-1942 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 17)
  - Speeches Material, 1932-1950; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 18-20)
  - Stevenson, Alice J., Legal File, 1954 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 21)
  - Stiles, Family War Record, 1942-1943 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 22)
  - Supreme Court of the United States, Petition for Rehearing, 1937 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 23)
  - Sweer, John H., Legal File, 1953-1955; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 24)
  - Syrigos, Antonios, Legal File, 1952-1959; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 25)
  - Tariff Speech, "The Menance to American Industry in the Proposal to Reduce the Tariff", 1945; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 26)
  - Theiss, William W. Legal File, 1954-1955; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 27)
  - Torjesen, EP Reverend (Immigration), 1954-1959 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 28)
  - Van Raalte, Legal File, 1931-1958 (Box 6 (1-Subject File), Folder 29-30)
  - Westchester County Bar Association, 1953-1959; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject File), Folder 1)
  - Weyerhauser Correspondence, 1933-1938 (Box 7 (1-Subject File), Folder 2-4)
  - Weyerhauser-Drafts, 1943; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject File), Folder 5)
  - Weyerhauser Lumber and National Lumber Correspondence, 1940-1942; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject File), Folder 6-9)
  - Weyerhauser Lumber Company Correspondence, 1939-1942 (Box 7 (1-Subject File), Folder 10-11)
  - Weyerhauser Lumber Company Printed Materials, 1941-1942; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject File), Folder 12-15)
  - Weyerhauser National Lumber Correspondence (Folder 1 of 3), 1940-1942 (Box 7 (1-Subject File), Folder 16)
  - Weyerhauser National Lumber Correspondence (Folder 2-3 of 3), 1940-1942 (Box 8 (1-Subject File), Folder 1-2)
  - Weyerhauser Printed Matter, Clippings, 1942-1943 (Box 8 (1-Subject File), Folder 3)
  - Weyerhauser, Washington Papers, 1942-1943; Undated (Box 8 (1-Subject File), Folder 4)
  - Winnetka Trip, 1953 May (Box 8 (1-Subject File), Folder 5)
  - Witschief, Graham and Margaret Correspondence, 1934-1947; 1952 (Box 9 (1-Subject File), Folder 3)
  - Wriedt, Hans F., 1954-1958 (Box 8 (1-Subject File), Folder 7)
  - Ying, Sui Fong, 1958-1959 (Box 8 (1-Subject File), Folder 8)
  - Zinke, Alexander F., 1933-1941; 1948-1955 (Box 8 (1-Subject File), Folder 9)
- Incoming Correspondence, 1884-1959; Undated; 2; 1.55 cubic ft.
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains correspondence received by William Stiles Bennet. Outside of a few brief items from the 1890s, material in this series dates from the years 1930 through 1959. It is arranged chronologically.
  - Incoming, 1884 January-1935 December 27 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Incoming, 1936 January 06-1937 September 28 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Incoming, 1937 October 01-1937 December 30 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Incoming, 1938 January 01-1938 April 29 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Incoming, 1938 May 04-1938 December 27 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Incoming, 1939 January 05-1939 August 22 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Incoming, 1939 September 01-1940 April 25 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Incoming, 1940 May 14-1940 December 26 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Incoming, 1941 January 02-1941 August 26 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Incoming, 1941 September 04-1941 December 30 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Incoming, 1942 January 02-1942 July 28 (Box 8 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Incoming, 1942 August 01-1942 December 28 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Incoming, 1943 January 02-1943 July 28 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Incoming, 1943 August 04-1944 April 26 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 1944 May 01-1944 December 30 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Incoming, 1945 January 06-1945 September 21 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Incoming, 1945 October 01-1945 December 31 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Incoming, 1946 January 03-1946 December 19 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Incoming, 1947 January 03-1947 October 30 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Incoming, 1947 November 01-1948 June 30 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Incoming, 1948 July 01-1948 December 30 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Incoming, 1949 January 30-1949 May 30 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Incoming, 1949 June 01-1950 April 29 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Incoming, 1950 May 02-1950 December 30 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Incoming, 1951 January 02-1951 December 27 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Incoming, 1952 January 13-1952 December 29 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Incoming, 1953 January 02-1954 December 28 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Incoming, 1957 January 07-1958 July 28 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Incoming, 1958 August 04-1959 June 01 (Box 9 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Incoming, 1955 January 01-1956 December 21 (Box 10 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Incoming, Undated (Box 10 (2-Incoming Correspondence), Folder 2)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1932-1959; Undated; 3; 1.28 cubic ft.
  This series contains outgoing correspondence sent by William Stiles Bennet. These materials date from the 1930s through the 1950s and are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Outgoing: A, 1937-1958 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Outgoing: B, 1934-1957 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Outgoing: C, 1935-1957 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Outgoing: D, 1937-1953; Undated (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 6-7)
  - Outgoing: F, 1932-1955 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Outgoing: G, 1937-1958 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Outgoing: H, 1932-1956; Undated (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 10-12)
  - Outgoing: I, J, K, 1933-1958; Undated (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Outgoing: L, 1933-1955 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Outgoing: M, 1933-1958 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Outgoing: N, 1933-1958 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 16-17)
  - Outgoing: O, 1933-1954 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Outgoing: P, 1935-1959 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 19-20)
  - Outgoing: Q, 1935-1957 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Outgoing: R, 1936-1959 (Box 10 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Outgoing: R, 1936-1959 (Box 11 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Outgoing: S, 1932-1958; Undated (Box 11 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 2-4)
  - Outgoing: T, 1937-1958 (Box 11 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Outgoing: U, V, 1932-1958 (Box 11 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Outgoing: W, 1937-1958 (Box 11 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 7-9)
  - Outgoing: X, Y, Z, 1935-1959 (Box 11 (3-Outgoing Correspondence), Folder 10)
- Political Materials and Oversized Items, 1888-1951; Undated; 4; 2.09 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials related to Bennet's various political campaigns as well as several oversized and fragile items. It includes a folder of speeches delivered by Bennet to the New York State Assembly in 1901-1902, several folders of material on Bennet's unsuccessful 1936 campaign for the Republican Vice Presidential nomination, and collections of political memorabilia from various campaigns. In addition, it includes several large scrapbooks, the transcription of an oral history interview with Bennet, tax reports from the town of Newburgh, a ledger dating from the late nineteenth century, and a collection of certificates documenting Bennet's election to various offices.
  - Assembly Speeches, 1901-1902 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 11)
  - Campaign, General, 1936-1938 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 12)
  - Certificates and Framed Items, 1904-1920; 1937-1951 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Congressional Campaign, 1936 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, General, 1888; 1932-1958; Undated (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Pertaining to 1910 Dinner (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 16)
  - Dated MSS Speeches, 1901-1914; 1921-1937; 1942 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 17-18)
  - Delegates Sent to the Republican National Convention, 1936 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 19)
  - Essays, Undated (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 20)
  - Family Genealogy, Undated (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 21)
  - "The Immigration Commission" featured in The Survey, 1910 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 22)
  - Ledger, 1897-1906 (Oversized 2)
  - Legislative Bill, Appointment as Official Referees of Court Justices, 1936 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 23)
  - Letters in Response, Results of 1936 Election (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1938; 1959; Undated (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 25)
  - Newburgh Tax Commission, Report of a Survey of Certain Departments of the Government of the City of Newburgh, NY, 1951 (Box 11 (4-Political Materials and Oversized Items), Folder 26)